#### Portal

A time when we were child playing football at that hot asphalt ground barefooted knowing nothing about this big word and it's not only that asphalt ground, and we can actually see the world from a different eyes, we were hearing the word Internet a lot as it was new in our region and how it let you talk with people very away from you, the very first time connecting to the Internet with two of my friends it was after the school I remember us running after the last class bell thinking how it will look, connecting that telephone extension cord into the pc, complete silence pervades the place while just listening to that dial up Internet connection it was unforgettable, that moment was the portal for me to dive into this technological world.

#### Me

As I grew up, witnessing the digital revolution and how it change the world and its impact on us but what was in my mind how we get all of this information there must be a place that coordinate all of this data and send it to whom request it, that's when I knew about data centers the name itself has its own charm it glueyed in me, from the very first field trip to the university data center I was stunned by that cold area, loud noise of hard drives and fans spinning, line of racks filled with servers and those colorful couples floating around it was indescribable moment.

Since then I never missed a trip to the university data center till those in charge of the tour came to know me.

I asked the university administration too many times to let me work there, finally after many requests they let me in as a Database operator trainee. Now as a senior student with only an internship course left to graduate, it will be thrilling to have my internship at the leader of Cloud services, I know that what I'm lacking is career experience.

However, the qualifications that I bring cannot be measured by traditional experience. enthusiast to gain more experience with trying to get the most from each summer break and get involved in the real work environment in multiple

position at the tech field the ability to come up with solution to fix a problem as one of my projects is building a program to organize crowding in the university restaurant, I learned how to multitask and prioritize responsibilities as those important for for individuals take part in a data center.

My studies in King Saud University include courses about Data structures, Database management, Data communications and computer networks will help to guide me in the right direction, as I'm now enrolled in online classes and getting more knowledge, I have a good foundation about data center infrastructure, good command on sql, linux systems, command-line interface.

Finally It would be a great chance to make the best use of my skills during my college study and to be helpful to your organization also shape my skills to align with your vision, to actually work in what I enjoy and I knew from every success story that with passion and hard work nothing Impossible I know that if you look to my resume you will see that I lean toward software but I also know that data centers where I want to be .

## AMER AL-SHABEBI

#### IT enthusiast and Full Stack Developer

B.S. in Information Systems, Interested in technology and the Digital transformation, lover of Data Centers, just thinking of that cold environment is awesome, Software Developer

Alaziziyah, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

#### +966567686161

in linkedin.com/in/amer-mohammed-444292180

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor's Degree, Information Systems**King Saud University

2016 - 2020

Courses

\_

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# It technician and Software Developer URWAY Technologies

05/2020 - Present

#### Tasks

- Working with the integration team
- on board customers to integrate with the payment gateway
- create php API to connect with the gateway and design sample web page for testing
- create ruby API to connect with the gateway and design sample web page code
- o collaborated in building Ecommerce plugin that use php
- collaborated in building java API

#### Database Operator

Deanship of e-Transaction and Communication King Saud University

02/2019 - 06/2019

#### Tasks

- trainee as SQL Developer
- maintenance building query for the database
- ensuring data quality
- providing information to others as needed and managing data integrity

### Web Developer

AlShaya Group

Tasks

- mainly workin on the front end
- integrate graphics of their merchandise into the website
- add new sign up option for user (facebook, google,etc...)
- Maintain website

## Data entry and help desk

**AL-Fanar for Advertisement** 

03/2017 - 08/2017 Tasks

#### • install OS

- install I/O devices and set up configuration
- insert employees data into their system

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS AND PERSONAL SKILLS

Problems Solving Self-Education Commitment

Multitasking PHP CSS HTML SQL

Linux System Ruby Python Flutter Java

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Arabic Kids Library

 an android app for audiobook with a Unique idea that allows volunteers to record their voice so that children can hear it

#### Get in line

 a program that generate a number for each one who click to organize the crowd in the university restaurant

#### **CERTIFICATES**

Databases using ORACLE (04/2019)

King Saud University

Cyber security (07/2019)

King Saud University

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

Professional Working Proficiency